

Ananthu Vasudev

Experiential Learning Strategist | Designing programs to make mistakes, identify skills, and become more sensible | Innovative | Featured on LinkedIn News | Brain of Evolvers

Kottayam, Kerala, India · www.ananthu.in

Contact: +91 9539 6999 49 e-mail: mail@ananthu.in

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ananthu-in

About

I have learned a lot from my experiences, from the people I met, and from my failures as well as successes and I keep all of these life lessons in mind all the time. Probably that's how I became an Experiential Learning Strategist who designs learning programs! I believe in evolution than education, and learning than teaching!

My life is all about 'experiential learning' and I choose my career on the same path! It was during my early college days, my father mentioned the need for a perfect finishing school to make the candidates employable; I started working on the same after 12 years, and The Evolvers Project Evolved.

We launched Evolvers with a unique experiential learning program - Intern-Preneur, which is a neo-internship kind of program where students and professionals can actually learn by doing. The program focuses on employability, and skill realization and helps in career as a whole.

Giving back something to society is always an important concept for me. I started my first NGO when I was 22, which could help a lot of students and families. I have been associated with various organizations such as ANTS, Say No To Harthal (State Convener), etc. Since 2012, I am associated with Government School for the Blind, Olassa, Kottayam, Kerala for each and every activity; initiated several projects for blind students to make them live like normal humans. I organized the first stem cell sample collection drive in Infopark, Kochi in association with Datri.



Entrepreneurship Experience



Founder & Chief Executive Officer

The Evolvers Project . Full-Time

Apr 2020 - Present . Kottayam, Kerala, India

Evolvers was conceived and established in 2020 with the primary focus to enhance students' competence and insights in different significant areas which are substantial to determine their success in professional and personal terrains. Our program is uniquely designed by scrutinizing the various elements restricting the students from being the best version of themselves.

Intern-Preneur Development Program is the signature program designed by Evolvers for employability enhancement, skill realization, skill evaluation, etc. We have other programs such as Intern-Preneur Foundation, Master of Intern-Preneur, Junior Intern-Preneur etc.

As the CEO, efficiently built the business from the scratch, created the team, initiated innovative ideas and projects, marketed with internal resources, and managed to gain two investors. Handled social media management, creative designs, video editing, video presenting, content management etc too along with regular responsibilities. Managed upto 20 member team including managers and interns too. Looking forward to expanding to South India and utilizing more technical resources in 12 months.



Co-Founder & Operations Head

The Bridge - Business Solutions May 2015 - April 2023 . Kochi, Kerala, India

The Bridge is a branding agency based in Kochi. Bridge focuses on helping clients through Brand storytelling, from creating a brand identity to strategy and implementation. Established in 2015, we had clients from Kerala, Tamil Nadu, Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka and other states, as well as from Dubai, UK, US and other countries. Co-founded the agency with three partners from the scratch. As the COO, handled the HR, Operations, ER, and Recruitment along with key roles in the creative department. I exited on April 2023.

Professional Experience



Manager: Operations & Governance

Aarogyamantra Integrated Healing Pvt Ltd 2017-2019 Kottayam, Kerala



General Manager

Swetaranya Ayurvedasram 2015-2016 Malappuram, Kerala



Manager - Operations

Vega Information Systems Pvt Ltd 2013-2015 Kochi, Kerala



Senior Products Operations Coordinator

Infosys BPM 2010-2012 Pune, Maharashtra

Education



Mahatma Gandhi University

Bachelor of Commerce (B.Com), Commerce & Computer Applications 2007 - 2010

Volunteering experience



State Convener

'Say No To Harthal' Campaign

July 2013 - Present Civil Rights & Social Action

- Say No To Harthal campaign works for a harthal free Kerala. The campaign is a non-violent protest against the violence and 'forcefully-support-seeking' system of political parties. The campaign has got national-level attention and the ex-Home Minister of Kerala himself initiated the step for the bill against harthal a few years back. Total number harthals were reduced over the period of years.
- Successfully handled the control room for Kochi on harthal days for over a year, and oversaw overall Operations of Kottayam District.



Program Co-Ordinator

 $\label{eq:Make A Wish - Govt. High School for the Blind, Olassa,, Kottayam$

Oct 2012 - Present.

Problem Solving Strategic Planning

Education & Differently Abled Community Development

- Associated with Government HS for the Blind and working closely with the Headmaster and PTA for the development of the school as well the students.
- Successfully raising funds and other needs for the students, schools, medical needs of students, etc. since 2012, coordinating various NGOs and a volunteer base of over a hundred youngsters, professionals, and veterans across Kerala.
- Improving the students' morale by taking them to movies, cycling, etc. Regularly conducted painting events by blind students and raised sold them as paintings, greeting cards, and calendars. Raised over 5 lakhs since 2017.
- Introduced the activities to other blind shools and NGOs as well.

Skills		
	Management	
	Endorsements	
	Team Management	
	Endorsements	
	Experiential Learning Strategy	
	Endorsements	
	Recruitment	Additional Acquired Skills:
	Operations Management	•
	Social Media Management	Creative Designing - Canva
	NGO Management	Video Editing - Filmora
	Creative Thinking	

Accomplishments and awards

- 4 ¦
- Languages

English . Malayalam . Hindi . Tamil

3

Honors and Awards

Angel of Kerala Flood . Arrow - Best Performer Award . RAMP Award by Infosys

Recommendations



Omar Ochoa

Quality Manager at TE Connectivity

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-ochoa-2a84b8a6/

At the time I had the opportunity to work with Ananthu he was a supplier of services for the company I was working for and having his support always with his characteristic will of service and supporting all the times he made it easier and productive. Ananthu's attitude towards his work group and his customers was always at a high level of professionalism and warm enough to enjoy working with him.



Richy D Alexander

Founder & CEO Davidson PR and Communication | Image Consultant

richy@davidsonpr.in | +91 98474 ****7

Ananthu is actively involved in various social responsible activities, he has been in forefront of few NGOs working for the betterment of specially abled kids. A truly self motivated humanitarian and go-getter who inspires his co-passengers always. I wish all the very best for his new venture The Evolvers Project.



PM Ramdas

Vice President | Head - Cyber Security at Reliance Group

p***mdas@gmail.com | 97*** 9***0

I've had the privilege of working with Ananthu for little more than 18 months now and in that time I have known him to be a well-grounded and down to earth techno-savvy and colleague. He is a calculated risk taker, pragmatic leader and realist who seem to grasp ideas holistically whilst still taking note to the more acute details. I found this to be incredibly valuable in working with him, as it allows him (and for those who work with him) the ability to explore and understand nearly all possible perspectives to an idea and its numerous applications. He is a hard worker and value creator in the truest sense. Actively participates in campaigns like "Say No to Hartal". Also decorates many senior posts in many altruistic organizations and finds time to cop up with them even in the midst of his busy professional life. Also being an enthusiastic bike rider, engages himself for the thrilling rides to the corners of the world. Without having a second thought, I would like to have him in my team.